#### Contact

+923345731825 (Mobile) m.hamid334@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/hafizmuhammad-hamid-892256101 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Programming
Databases
C++

Languages

English

# Hafiz Muhammad Hamid

Senior Software Engineer | .NET | .NET Core | GRPC | Microservices | RabbitMQ | Kubernetes | DevOps | SQL SERVER Lahore District

## Summary

I am a Senior Software Engineer having more than 7 years of experience in .Net Framework. I worked on ERP and created various applications for SZABIST Islamabad including jobPortal, Bio-Matric attendance application by using .Net framework | MS Azure | DevOps | (C#| Asp.Net | .Net MVC| .Net Core |.Net Core Microservices) | Grpc | Proto buf | Kubernetes | Docker | Entity framework | Dapper | BootstrapWeb API | SQL server A professional with a MSCS degree from SZABIST.

## Experience

OutsourceNZ
Senior Software Engineer
July 2019 - Present (2 years 9 months)
Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

development of .NET Core based app using grpc, microservices and Kubernetes.

Shaheed Zulfikar Ali Bhutto Institute of Science and Technology Islamabad Campus

5 years 4 months

Software Application Developer April 2014 - July 2019 (5 years 4 months)

#### Lab Demonstrator

September 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 4 months) Islamabad

Taught Programming Fundamentals as a lab course.

International Islamic University Islamabad Pakistan Teaching Assistant
January 2013 - June 2013 (6 months)

Islamabad

Assisted Object Oriented Programming as a course.

### Education

Shaheed Zulfikar Ali Bhutto Institute of Science and Technology Islamabad Campus

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science · (2015 - 2017)

International Islamic University, Islamabad BSCS, Software Development · (2009 - 2013)